是詹妮弗·威廉姆斯吗
Jennifer Williams?
你是...
And you are?
塞勒斯  塞勒斯·哈里
Cyrus. Cyrus Harry?
你以前老是叫我小塞
You used to call my Cy if it's--
如果那个人是你的话
if it's really you.
我一直在找这个詹妮弗·威廉姆斯
I--I'm trying to find the Jennifer Williams
23年前我就认识她了
I knew 23 years ago.
我们在泽西海滨共度长假
We spent a long weekend at the Jersey Shore?
当时她在拜访朋友
She was visiting a friend...
这次去的时间有点长
That lasted longer than usual.
兰斯代尔走完了
That's it for Lansdale.
收拾一下
Pack it up.
我们去费城
Let's move on to Philly.
别这样  你是要闹脾气吗
Seriously, you gonna complain?
有多少轿车司机薪水能达到六位数啊
How many limo drivers are making six figures?
塞  我亲爱的表弟  我爱你
Cy, you're my little cousin, and I love you,
你真是太慷慨了
and you've been more than generous.
你把时间浪费在那逝去的回忆上
I'm upset because you are wasting your time
所以我有些烦躁
over some faded memory
你竟然放着眼前的花花世界不要
when there is a world of pleasure out there.
你的那些钱够你买下多少乐趣啊
The kind of cash you got buys a lot of it.
好了  我不该那样的
Come on. ...be like that.
我只是开车兜了一整天圈子
I've just been driving around all day.
有点疲倦了
I'm a little cranky.
我的腿不能动了
My leg won't move.
你是准备就这么看着
Are you gonna stare,
还是帮忙打911
or are you gonna call 911?
局部麻痹
Partial paralysis.
头颅CT和腰椎穿刺无异常
Head CT and LP showed nothing.
脊髓MRI和肌电图也没问题
Spinal MRIs and EMG were clean.
是脑部症状
Brain symptom,
但他的大脑现在还没什么问题
yet nothing seems to be wrong with his brain.
冰箱维修工  没有家人  工作不稳定
Refrigerator mechanic, no family, in and out of work.
他买国营彩票刚中了4200万
He just won $42 million in the state lottery.
这就是我在报纸上看到的那个幸运的家伙
I think I read about this lucky bastard in the paper.
你确定这个家伙很幸运吗
You sure you don't mean the lucky bastard
指不定他的孙子为了吸毒
whose grandkids snorted his winnings
挥金如土  吸得怎么死的都不知道呢
till he drank himself to death with drain cleaner?
或者他自己被发现在夜店的停车场
Or the lucky bastard who was found naked and penniless
全身赤裸  身无分文
in a strip club parking lot
他的蛋蛋上还印着中奖号码
with his winning number tattooed on both testicles?
耳神经病变
Neuro-otological pathology
会引起平衡觉丧失
could have caused loss of balance.
冷热水交替实验结果正常
Calorics were normal.
有些人会把事情弄糟
Sure, some people will screw up anything,
有些人不会
but some won't.
有那些钱
That kind of cash,
足够他咸鱼翻身了
he has a chance to turn a miserable life around.
咸鱼终究还是咸鱼
Miserable stays miserable.
首先  幸福的话就不会去买彩票
Happy doesn't buy lottery tickets in the first place.
我们的幸福感是不会变的
Our level of happiness is set.
那是DNA决定的
It's in our DNA.
这不是有钱就可以改变的
No cash payout's gonna change that.
你真是说出了我的心声
It's like there's two of me.
那个人是修电器的
The guy repairs appliances.
他可能因为常年在含有有毒气体的环境中工作
He's probably got toxic brain damage
而导致中毒性脑损伤
from years of working with toxic chemicals.
或者是横财带来的横祸
Or his sudden disease came from his sudden millions.
他买了些东西  或收集了些东西
He's buying something, collecting something,
陶器  贵重金属
ceramics, precious metals,
致使他的颈动脉发生动脉粥样硬化
which gave him atherosclerosis of his carotid arteries.
我母亲的律师打电话来了
My mother's lawyer called.
她扬言要起诉
She's threatening to sue the hospital
说这家医院治疗不当
over our mistreatment of her.
影响了她的复原
Says it slowed her recovery.
我刚还在想呢
You know, I was just thinking
我是有多想要一段无性关系
how much I want a relationship with no sex
却还非得应付你母亲
but where I still have to deal with your mother.
去患者之前的工作车间
Go to the patient's old workshop.
找出中毒性脑损伤的原因
Look for causes of toxic brain damage.
去问问他现在的生活状况
Go take a new history,
看看是否存在生活习惯的改变
and see if there's any lifestyle changes
可以解释动脉粥样硬化
that would explain atherosclerosis.
你也走吧
Go.
先吃药
Medicinal.
你就尽量发挥让我头疼吧
I'm expecting a shooting pain in my ass.
我和我妈吵得不可开交
My mom and I got into a fight.
因为我们重新做了髋关节置换
Because of our replacement hip replacement,
她在自己家里行动不便
she can barely get around her own house.
我跟她说了  在她恢复期间要跟我住一起
I told her she has to live with me while she recovers.
我找到联系了
Oh, I'm starting to get the connection.
她有一所房子[她拥有豪斯]
Yeah, she has a house,
我的名字叫豪斯
my name is House.
你是她真正的主治师
You're the doctor that treated her,
在被解雇后  你非法改变她的服药剂量
that illegally switched her meds after she fired you,
还在她的主治师背后暗箱操作
that went behind the back of her actual doctor.
几百年前的旧账了
Those beads from Thailand.
如果非要一一清算
If we're listing all the things
所有你强迫我做的事的话
that you pressured me into.
关键在于  这事你撇不开责任
The point is you're the who's on the line here,
你的名字在她的住院记录上
whose name is on her hospital records.
谁的名字又在她名字上面
Whose name is on her name?
好吧
Fine.
我们都是一根绳上的蚂蚱
We're both on the line,
但她不愿和我单方面解决此事
but she won't discuss this with me alone.
她和她的律师要求同我们两个
She and her lawyer want to meet with both of us
进行和解谈判
for settlement talks.
我需要你到场  并且为了化解此事
I need you in that meeting acting nice and respectful
你得表现出和善而有礼貌
while I defuse this stunt.
好吧  我不会去的
Yeah well, I'm not going to that meeting,
这样如果我既不和善也不礼貌
so I'm guessing you're cool
你也不会发火了
if I'm not nice and respectful either.
有什么新嗜好吗
Picked up any new hobbies?
一个嗜好怎么会让我的左腿瘫痪
How's a hobby gonna paralyze my left leg?
如果你在古董车行工作
If you work on vintage cars
或者做油漆工
or you've taken up painting,
那些气味会
the fumes can...
没在车行做事  也没有涂漆
No cars, no paints.
你可真受欢迎啊
You're a popular guy.
钱包受欢迎而已
Popular wallet.
三年前  在我中奖之前
Three years ago, before I had a dime.
我做了阑尾炎切除手术
I had my appendix out.
菲尔当时在  连个电话都没人打给我
Phil was there. No one else even called.
有吸毒史吗
What about drugs?
没有
No drugs.
听着  我看了不少纪录片
Look, I've seen all the documentaries,
也读过很多文章
I've read all the articles.
我不会有钱就学坏
I'm not gonna be a tabloid cliche.
我知道该怎么用这些钱
I know what I'm gonna do my money.
找到这辈子唯一的真爱
Find and build a life
一起建立我们的新生活
with the one woman I ever cared for.
重点是什么都没变
The point is nothing's changed.
我依然过着同样的生活  吃着同样的食物
I live the same life. I eat the same food.
一样劣质的罐装食品
Same crappy canned food.
你一天有几餐是吃罐头
How many of your meals do you eat from a can?
大多数都是
Most of 'em.
我已经习惯了
I'm used to it.
我在网上订购
I order 'em by the case online.
有什么问题吗
Is that bad?
你在担心卡迪母女和豪斯的
You're worried about the trickle down effect
三人火拼会殃及到病人
of Cuddy versus House versus Cuddy.
你是在解读我的内心世界吗
You're reading subtext into my silence?
豪斯比其他人更懂得怎么刺激你
House gets to you more than anyone.
豪斯认为我是个机器人
House thinks I'm a robot.
你觉得我很没用吗
You think I'm a wuss?
不  不是
No, no, no, no.
我觉得你是太压抑了
I think you're repressed.
当然  这也不能怪你
Well, it's out of your control.
艰难的童年
Tough childhood,
紧张的家庭关系
strained relations with your family.
在白人的世界里难以成功
Can't be easy trying to succeed in a white man's world.
首先  别拿人种说事
First of all, white man,
我的工作能力至少跟你相当
I've done at least as well as you have.
第二  我觉得你并不认同豪斯所认为的
Second, I didn't think you take House's view
生活糟糕而我们身陷其中不得解脱
that life sucks and we're stuck.
我觉得你确实陷进去了
I think you're stuck.
大概是上个月  我的生活变了样
Last month or so I've turned my life around.
我比以前开心多了
I'm happier than ever.
睡的女人比以前的更多了吗
Sleeping with ten women instead of four?
一个都没有
Try none.
他在切割金属  是因为吸入粉尘吗
He was cutting metal... Inhaled the dust?
除非他像吸毒那样吸入粉尘
Unless he was snorting lines of the stuff.
一个都没有吗
None?
长期的做爱
Was having tons of sex,
让我觉得很无聊  自己都痛恨自己
and I was bored, hating myself.
当真爱来临时  我却没有做好准备
Was never gonna be ready when something real came along.
你能变成一个超级修道士
So you're becoming some kind of super monk,
我却只能是老样子
and I can't change at all.
我赌如果豪斯或其他人让你不爽
I challenge you to go one differential
你内心都会压着这股气
without House or anyone else getting under your skin.
不过我说了没什么能够影响我
Since I say nothing gets to me
而你又不相信我的话
and you won't take me at my word,
我要怎么证明你是错的呢
how am I supposed to prove you wrong?
我想你大概没法证明
I guess you can't.
希望你不会因此而纠结不已
I hope that doesn't eat at you.
未注册商标的溶剂  中国产的
Off-brand solvent. From China.
鬼才知道成分是什么
Made of God knows what.
又是一例患者食用廉价罐头食品的案例
Patient eats cheap canned goods by the caseload.
会是金属中毒吗
Could be metal poisoning?
他还和廉价的化学药品打交道
He also worked with cut-rate chemicals.
可能是吸入挥发性有毒物质
Could be inhalation of a toxic volatile substrate.
螯合疗法能治疗这两种可能
Treatment for both is chelation.
干得好
Great work.
碱化他的尿液并利尿
Alkalinize his urine and force diuresis
以治疗重金属中毒
for heavy metal poisoning.
如果不管用  再做透析来治疗有毒物质
If that doesn't work, put him on dialysis for toxic inhalation.
我刚说了  螯合剂可以兼治两者
I just said treatment for both is chelation.
我说先利尿  再做个透析
And I said force diuresis and try dialysis.
你没有听清吗
You need a transcript?
在螯合剂就能治疗的情况下
You want to put him on dialysis,
你要他冒着感染
risk infection and hemodynamic swings
和血流动力学改变的风险做透析吗
when we can just chelate?
大家冷静点
Settle down.
如果我们用螯合剂
If we chelate,
我们就不知道他得了什么病
we're not gonna know what disease he had,
我们就不会知道问题是出在
which means we're not gonna know if the problem
以前糟糕的职业上
was in his lousy old job
还是如今依旧很糟糕的生活上
or his still-lousy new life.
为了解决我们刚才的争论
Which for the purposes of a metaphorical argument
答案很重要
is very important.
没什么好反对的
Pointless to argue.
他是老板  老板说了要玩解迷游戏
He's the boss. He needs his puzzle solved.
我们干嘛要违逆他呢
Why bang our heads against the wall?
病人那边处理好以后
When you're done with the patient,
治治福曼吧  拿他的头多撞几下墙
treat Foreman by banging his head against the wall.
透析仪呢
Where's the dialysis machine?
管它呢  我预约了做螯合治疗
Who cares? Since I ordered chelation.
我们抛硬币来决定告诉豪斯哪个是病因
We'll flip a coin, tell House it was one disease or the other.
最不济反抗暴露了  他则对我们刮目相看
Worst case, he finds out and he's impressed we defied him.
不好意思  我是叫你撤掉透析仪
I'm sorry. I asked you to remove the dialysis equipment,
没叫你撤掉螯合仪器
not the chelation equipment.
卡迪医生叫我撤掉所有仪器
And Dr. Cuddy asked me to remove all equipment.
她通知要中止所有治疗
She de-authorized all treatment.
她不让我们做任何治疗
She won't let us make a move
除非你同意坐下来
until you agree to a sit-down
和教母大人以及她的律师谈谈
with the godmother and her consigliere.
她够狠的
Bitch to king four.
没招了
Checkmate.
病人的腿动不了
Patient can't use his leg.
你这次必须妥协
You have to concede.
或者我还可以选择撒手不管
Or I could just knock all the pieces onto the floor.
你们要我出院吗
You're discharging me?
我们实在是
We really...
编不出什么好的谎话来...
don't have a good lie here, so...
我们的头头和他的上司发生摩擦
You got caught in some politics
你不幸做了炮灰
between our boss and his boss,
但最多让你出院二十分钟
but you'll be out of here 20 minutes tops.
我的病还没治好  你们就想撵我走吗
I'm not better, but you're kicking me out?
所以我说你出院不会超过二十分钟
Which is why it'll only be 20 minutes.
院长这次很强硬  但她强硬不到哪里
See, the Dean of Medicine acts tough, but she's not really.
不久她就会干预  然后重新收你入院
She'll step in, readmit you.
你是说比起那位不作为的医生
So you're saying that she cares more about his treatment
反而是她更在意病人的治疗状况吗
than the doctor who's actually treating him.
菲尔  闭嘴
Phil, shut up.
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
詹妮弗
Jennifer.
能见到你真好
It's good to see you.
我在报纸上读到了有关你的报道
I read about you in the paper,
便跳上了第一列从弗吉尼亚开来的火车
so I hopped the first train from Virginia.
就是说你看到他一夜暴富的消息  是吧
So you read that he struck it rich?
他说的对
He's right.
我突然过来  看起来肯定很古怪
It--it must look weird.
确实有点古怪
It kind of is weird.
距我们去第三大道堤坝玩耍已经好久了
Well, we're a long way from the third street jetty.
我就是想来再看看你  问声好
I just wanted to see you again and say hi,
你好
So. Hi.
我几乎要以为再也找不到我的...
I was starting to think I'd never find my...
熊宝宝
Baby bear.
天哪  对不起
Oh, my God. I'm--I'm so sorry.
实在是不好意思
I'm so sorry.
我一点儿都没觉得恶心
I--I don't even feel nauseous.
-我不知道怎么就...  -你手在抖
- I don't know why... - Your hand is shaking. Okay.
是局灶性癫痫发作
You're having a focal seizure.
这是什么情况
What does that mean?
就是说你不用出院了
It means you're not getting discharged.
是大脑的问题  我们猜对了
We were right that it's a brain issue,
但却不是因为金属中毒或者吸入有毒粉尘
but wrong about toxic inhalation and metal poisoning.
其他人都在等着呢
Everyone else is waiting--
克洛伊[模特]真是够勇敢
That was totally courageous of Khloe
居然在微博上讲自己胖了
to Tweet about her weight gain.
豪斯  病人无法走路并伴有癫痫
House, I've got a patient with a seizure disorder who can't walk.
又来了一个这样的吗
Another one?
还以为我们刚赶走了最后一个呢
Thought we kicked out the last one.
显然  我会同意让你治疗那个病人
Obviously I'll let you treat your patient.
你做什么呢
What are you doing?
咱们的病人无法癫痫并伴有步行症
We got a patient with a walking disorder who can't seize.
等等  不对  但我说的很接近了是吧
No, wait. I'm close, though, right?
我没说完呢
I wasn't finished.
显然我会同意你治疗他
Of course I'll let you treat your patient
前提是你我各退一步
if you meet me halfway.
那看来我也没休息够呢
Well, I guess I'm not finished either.
下个季度你不用出诊了
No clinic hours for the next quarter.
再给我三个紧挨着的停车位
Yeah, three parking spots,
让我能够斜着停车
next to each other, so I can park diagonally,
我还要你三套内衣
and three pairs of your underwear.
我在考虑航海呢
I'm thinking of taking up sailing.
算了
Forget it.
病人你爱治不治
Treat your patient, don't treat your patient.
会面你爱来不来
Come to the meeting, don't come to the meeting.
我不再陪你玩游戏了
I'm done playing your game.
输家认输后游戏就自动结束了
You realize the game is automatically over
你是知道的对吧
when the loser loses, right?
神经莱姆病
Neurological Lyme disease
可以解释癫痫和瘫痪症状
explains the seizures and the paralysis.
但无法解释为什么奇斯在测量你的指标
But not the fact that Chase seems to be treating you.
他自称可以永远不再做爱
He claims he can swear off sex indefinitely.
还声称我是个压抑满腹怒火的滚水锅
Also claims that I am a boiling cauldron of repressed rage.
你的理论蠢透了
Your theory is idiotic.
病人的莱姆病抗体滴度呈阴性
The patient's antibody titers were negative for Lyme disease.
我和你前女友曾在一间旅店里同房共寝
And I shared a motel room with your ex-girlfriend.
关于抗体滴度的问题  你说的很对
You make a good point about the antibody titers.
他还真是块石头
He's a rock.
你弟弟怎样了  那个无家可归的家伙
How's your brother-- homeless guy?
好久没他的消息了吧
Haven't heard from him in months!
我不知道  希望我有他消息
I don't know. Wish I did.
体位性低血压
Postural hypotension,
这会导致大脑的血供减少
which could have reduced the blood supply to his brain.
那他可真是个倒霉蛋
He'd be a miserable wretch.
实际上  预后的...
Actually, the prognosis is--
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我只是想说他的人生前景一片黑暗
No, I just meant his life is gonna unravel.
客观来讲  任何诊断结果都是一样的
In fairness, that applies to any diagnosis.
我们干嘛讨论这个
Why do we do this?
不是体位性低血压  他当时没在站着
It's not postural hypotension. He's not orthostatic.
他的生活可能会崩塌  也可能不会
His life may unravel, it may not.
他并不追求物质享受
He's not chasing after material things.
真糟  他本能好好享受的
Too bad. He might actually get those.
他寻找的是爱情
He's looking for love.
找寻旧日女友
Just tracked down an old girlfriend.
而最终找到的人却和记忆里相差甚远
And she'll never live up to the memory,
找到她的激动感也会烟消云散
and the thrill of finding her will wear off,
他以后连憧憬幸福的可能都没有了
and he won't even be able to dream about being happy.
有意思
Interesting.
他或许找到了许久以前的女伴
The patient may have found some long-ago nookie,
但这并不表示在这期间他一直守身如玉
but it doesn't mean he hasn't had some in the meantime.
疱疹病毒性脑炎
Herpes encephalitis.
可以解释神经系统症状
Explains the neurological symptoms.
做脑电图确诊
EEG to confirm,
然后静脉滴注阿昔洛韦治疗
I.V. Acyclovir to treat.
福曼的血压怎么样了
How's Foreman's BP holding?
还那样
Same.
那就怪了
That's strange,
因为我半分钟前刚拔掉了导线
since I unplugged the lead 30 seconds ago.
多了不起的忍耐力
Admirable effort.
我这么说可不是因为我担心你发火
And I'm not just saying that 'cause I'm scared you might turn green
或者扯烂你自己的衣服
and rip through your own clothes.
对病人的浪漫情怀不屑一顾
Down on the patient's romance
是因为你的寿命已短到撑不过一次约会了吗
because your own lifespan is shorter than dinner and a movie?
不幸的人注定不幸  这可是你说的
You're the one who said miserable stays miserable.
而你把它挂在嘴边  一天重复好几遍
You keep saying it. Several times a day.
回来工作太让我开心了
I love being back,
每个你我都认同的观点
having every theory you and I share
都被你用来证明我的人生残缺不堪
used as proof of my own personal damage.
恐怕一会开始脑电图检查后
I'm afraid we'll need you to step out
你得去外面等待
when the EEG begins.
等候区就在下面大厅里
The waiting area's just down the hall.
没关系  反正我要坐早班车走的
I got to catch an early train in the morning anyway.
别  别走
No, don't.
我可以给你安顿一家好点的酒店
I'll put you up in a nice hotel,
或者给你租一间带家具的房子
or rent you a furnished place.
我连夜赶来  只是想看看你生活得如何
I came for the night 'cause I wanted to see how you were.
也许有想重新成为你生活的一部分
Maybe get back in your life a bit,
但如果我接受你的钱...
but if I take your money...
给你找个好地方住有什么问题
What's wrong with a nice place to stay?
当然了  除非是
Unless of course...
你不想留下来
You don't want to stay.
或许我的旅馆房间还可以再续一两天
I guess I could keep my motel room another night or two.
帮我会会诊
Need a consult.
给病人做了脑电图
Did an EEG on my patient.
结果表明  前几个医生
Turns out the reason that prior doctors
之所以认为那不是神经系统疾病
thought it wasn't a neuro problem
是因为确实不是神经系统疾病
is because it's not a neuro problem.
但脑电图确实显示有代谢障碍的迹象
The EEG did show signs of metabolic distress.
那就扫描他的腹部
Well, scan his abdomen.
是啊  不妨假设我们已经完成这一步了
Yeah, let's assume we'd already figured that out on our own,
并且在胰腺发现一个肿块
and found a mass on the pancreas.
肿块看上去是实性的  要我说就是癌症
Mass looks solid. I'd say it's cancer.
副瘤综合征可以解释神经系统症状
Paraneoplastic syndrome would explain the neurological symptoms.
得取出一小块检查检查
You need to get a piece of it.
预约做个CT引导下活检吧
Schedule a CT-guided biopsy.
是啊  不妨假设我们这一步也完成了
Yeah, let's assume we'd already figured that out on our own.
那你还来找我会诊干什么
Then what's this consult?
卡迪母女俩的事  你怎么都没冲我嚷嚷
Why haven't you been yelling at me about the Cuddy twins?
因为你做得没错
Because you're doing the right thing.
我们是在说同一件事吗
Are we talking about the same issue?
还是我做了什么
Is there something I don't know about
自己都没意识到的正确举动吗
that I'm responding to appropriately?
卡迪希望你能介入这件事
Cuddy wants you in the middle of this.
艾琳也这么想
So does Arlene.
因为她们不愿正视自己的问题
Because they don't want to face their own problem.
而你那些出于本能的幼稚行为
Somehow, in your knee-jerk, juvenile way,
却歪打正着  是成熟的应对方式
you tripped and fell into an actual adult response to this.
你说的对
You're right.
这自始至终都是卡迪的计策
That was Cuddy's strategy all along.
她想让我以为
She wanted me to think
如果我不去  她就完蛋了
that she desperately needed me to be there
于是我就肯定不会去了
so that I wouldn't be there.
豪斯医生在哪里
Where is Dr. House?
我不想让他来
I didn't want him here.
这与她在普林斯顿医院接受的治疗无关
This isn't about her treatment at Princeton-Plainsboro.
只是因为我们上周大吵了一架
It's about the fight we had last week.
我想和我妈单独呆会
I'd like a moment with my mother
看看我俩能否自己解决这问题
to try and work this out on our own.
恐怕我的委托人不希望
I'm afraid my client doesn't want to--
这个周日就是母亲节了
It's mother's day Sunday.
我们就不能单独聊五分钟来化解矛盾吗
We can't have five minutes alone to fix this?
放松  你站在外面这段时间
Relax. You can still bill me
我也会付你钱的
for the time standing in the hallway.
我知道你很生气
I know you're mad at me,
但你自己上下楼都很困难
but you can barely make it up those stairs.
你有多少晚上都是睡在沙发上的
How many nights have you spent on your couch?
这和我们之间的争吵无关
This has nothing to do with our fight.
我们说的是我家  不是战俘集中营
We're talking about my home, not a prison camp.
我刚才说过了
What did I just say?
我认为这事不要夹杂私人恩怨
I think it was something about this not being personal.
你可以有时间和瑞秋在一起
You can spend time with Rachel.
我可以照顾你
I can watch over you.
双赢
Win, win.
也许我身体是不太好
Maybe I've got a medical thing.
也许我只是自顾自说
Maybe I just think I'm talking,
而没人愿认真听我说
but no one can hear me,
不只是我那漠不关心的女儿
not just my uncaring daughter.
你想怎样
What do you want?
两万
20 grand.
我会雇人照看并忘记你带给我的这些破事
I'll hire help and forget this nightmare you put me thr--
三万好了  我会安个电梯的
make it 30. I'll put in a stair lift.
不要说是和解  就是你提出的这些条件
If my board even hears about these threats,
如果被董事会听到了
let alone a settlement,
他们会调查你在医院期间
they'll investigate what happened
发生了什么
while you were here as a patient.
我和豪斯都会丢了行医执照的
House and I could both lose our licenses.
我本以为这是私人恩怨
I've been assuming this is personal
因为我不愿相信
because I don't want to assume
那才是我母亲想要的结果
that was what my mother wants.
豪斯
House.
前非岳母
Ex-not-mom-in-law.
你说过你不会来的
You said you weren't coming.
在你对我说了那么多甜言蜜语以后吗
After you said pretty please with sugar on top?
问题是我们这只换货不退款
Problem is we only give store credit,
按我说不如把那个破烂有毒髋部放回去
so I say we put your old, cracked poisonous hip back in.
就在此时此地
Here and now.
我救了你的命
I saved your life.
你不喜欢的话可以还给我
Happy to un-save it.
他最近很混蛋
He is being an ass.
我也想和你一起起诉他...
If I could join you in suing him--
我们上床时她也喜欢我这么做
She's like this in bed too.
想方设法把律师赶走  再趁人之危
Always scheming to get the lawyers out of the room.
如果豪斯不想认真对待此事
If House isn't going to take this seriously,
我知道有些法官会的
I know a few judges who will.
我刚才该唱白脸吗
Was I supposed to be the good cop?
我也是不得已才作假的
I had to rig the monitor.
我早饭时吃了很多盐
I had a lot of salt with breakfast.
你也觉得我抑郁了
You think I'm repressed too?
我觉得你快被
I think you're in danger of being dissolved
肚子里的酸水给溶了
by your own stomach acids.
那奇斯呢
Well, what about Chase?
你相信他独善其身的那套废话吗
Believe all that nonsense about him being celibate?
我不知道  不过我支持他
Don't know, but I'm rooting for him.
我看过一些研究说
Read the studies.
你的床上朋友越少
The fewer partners you have,
你和终身伴侣就越幸福快乐
the happier you are with your ultimate partner.
没错  那你可就悲剧了
Then you're gonna be miserable.
那些研究
The studies,
重要的是要有对照组
it's important that they have a control group.
他的胰腺处有个肿瘤
There's the tumor on his pancreas.
肾脏和结肠处也各有一个
There's one on his kidney and one in his colon.
一个像非血管源性肿瘤
One looks avascular,
一个像血管源性肿瘤
one looks vascular.
第三个像钙化性占位
The third looks calcifie
他同时患有三种不同类型的癌症
he has three completely different cancers at once.
总体来说  他可不怎么走运
On average, not so lucky after all.
你拿我当灰太郎耍阿
You had to go all Wile E. Coyote on me.
是你告诉我艾琳想让我参与其中的
You told me that Arlene wanted me in the middle of it.
我已经让她明白这样不会有好结果的
I had to show her that no good would come of that.
不是吧  你就不能理性地处理这事吗
Seriously? That's your rationalization?
这理由怎么样  你不喜欢卡迪耍了你
How about you didn't like that Cuddy tricked you?
即使你俩的最终目的相同
Even though you wanted the same thing as her.
你不喜欢她赢你
You didn't like that she got the best of you.
你对她的愤怒远超过你的想像
You've got more anger toward her than you realize.
没了她我过得更快活
I'm happier without her.
我才不会愚蠢地认为她能让我变得幸福
I'm not stupidly expecting her to make me happy.
我更满意自己现在不幸福的状态
I'm happier with my unhappiness.
你知道你刚才在说什么吗
Do you listen to what you're saying?
可我一直都有听你胡言乱语
Because I have to.
我要开次峰会  你和卡迪都得来
I'm holding a summit meeting to force you and Cuddy
在我们收到一纸诉状前  统一战线
onto the same page before a lawsuit gets filed.
三种完全不相关的癌症同时存在
Three completely unrelated cancers at once.
多癌综合症  希佩尔林道病吗
Multi-cancer syndrome-- Von Hippel Lindau?
那不会影响到他的结肠
Wouldn't have touched his colon.
我在此证明
I hereby certify that
福曼医生没有在这台血压计上
Dr. Foreman has not tampered with
动任何手脚
this blood pressure mechanism in any way.
在我证明我根本就没有压抑自己后
And after I prove I'm 100% stress free,
我能给你系条贞操带吗
do I get to strap you into a chastity belt?
如果是患者缺失了一个抑癌基因呢
What if the patient's missing a tumor-suppressor gene?
那要怎么查出来
How would we even find it?
咱们现在就得给他化疗了
We need to blast him with chemo now.
我们不能给病人化疗
We can't give the patient chemo.
他的血小板计数已经跌至谷底了
His platelet count's through the floor.
更糟的是  那会遏制他的癌症
Even worse, it'd contain his cancers.
如果想知道这些癌症有什么共同点
If we want to know what they have in common,
就得看看癌症接下来会扩散到哪里
we got to see where they spread next.
你想再等六个月  放任他的癌症扩散
You want to wait six months while the cancer spreads
而让癫痫和瘫痪恶化吗
and his seizures and paralysis get worse?
这是有点疯狂
Well, now, that's crazy talk.
不过如果我们给病人
But if we pump the patient
输入大量血管内皮生长因子
full of vascular endothelial growth factor...
福曼不喜欢这主意
Foreman doesn't like that idea.
你想引发更多更大的肿瘤吗
You want to grow more and bigger cancers?
我们没办法弄清楚那三个小肿瘤的共同点
We can't figure out what three small ones have in common,
也许再有八个大肿瘤我们就能明白了
maybe can figure out what eight big ones have in common?
你是真的这么打算
Is this idea real,
还是只是想通过威胁杀死病人来刺激我
or are you just threatening to kill the patient to screw with me?
这整件事太白痴了
This whole thing is idiotic.
只要我知道如何控制情绪
What does it matter what's inside of me
压抑不压抑又有什么关系呢
if I know how to control it?
对我们没所谓
Makes no difference to us,
不过你也许想立个遗嘱
but you may want to make out a will.
去让那个彩票病人签字
Go get lotto boy's consent,
然后让他的肿瘤长到十一个
and turn his cancers up to 11.
怎么  你找到我的旧年鉴
You, what, found my old yearbook,
发现了我高中男友的照片吗
and got a picture of my high school boyfriend?
实际上  没那么复杂
Actually, that would have been a lot simpler.
我十分钟之前刚拍的
I took this ten minutes ago.
你的高中男友甩了你
Your high school boyfriend who dumped you,
让你不再相信
leaving you unable to believe
旧情复燃这种事
that anyone can rekindle an old flame.
他是在我和他妹搞到一起后才甩的我
He dumped me after I hooked up with his sister.
你能委婉地拒绝他吗
Would you mind letting him down gently?
我貌似说了些你无法信守的大话
I might have made promises you can't keep.
我们要让你得更多的癌症
We're giving you more cancer.
这事的风险不言而喻
The risks of that are kind of obvious.
我们会频繁地扫描并检测你的血液
We'll scan you, run your blood at frequent intervals.
我们坚信这是找出
We believe this is our best chance
你潜在的遗传缺陷的最佳办法
at finding the underlying genetic flaw.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
如果我被癌症打败
If this cancer overwhelms me,
我至少可以幸福的死去
at least I'll die happy here and now,
而不是在对无望的未来的憧憬中离开
instead of hoping for a future I may never have.
我爱你
I love you.
不  并非如此
No, you don't.
你不知道也不可能知道你是否爱我
You don't know. You can't know.
我们彼此都需要更多的时间
We both need more time.
我相信我们会有未来的
And I believe we're gonna have it.
你注意到她每天都穿不同的衣服吗
Do you notice she's wearing different clothes every day?
与一成不变的病号服相对比吗
As opposed to the same, starfleet-issued tunic?
她说她只计划留一个晚上
She said she came for one night.
为什么带了那么多衣服
Why'd she pack for more?
她在包里多放了件毛线衫
So she stuffed an extra sweatshirt in her bag,
或者她新买了衣服
or she bought something.
买二手的吗  她来就是为了这个爆发户
Used? She's here because an old beau struck gold.
她拒绝了求婚
She turned down a proposal.
你觉得她这场戏要演多久
How long a game you think she's playing?
我觉得如果她十四个小时后同意了
I think if she said yes after 14 hours,
他也会怀疑的
even he'd be suspicious.
作为才貌双全的女人你很幸运  因为
You're lucky you're hot and smart, because--
才貌双全真的是很幸运了
well, you're just lucky you're hot and smart.
我要找个妓女
I need a hooker.
如果你练瑜伽有效就不用了
Not if you can make that work.
那样怎么能放松呢
How is that supposed to relax you?
不是我  是奇斯
It's not for me. It's for Chase.
我也想要
I'm saving myself too.
不如你多找一个跟他组队好了
Maybe you should get a couple.
你总是找我麻烦  为什么不找他呢
You're riding me. Why not ride him?
因为我能让你血压升高
Because I can get a rise out of your BP.
却只能让他更"性奋"
His pp on the other hand...
放弃瑜伽信奉禅宗吧
Forget yoga. Embrace Zen.
你就是忧郁的白痴
You're a repressed idiot.
他是个性感的白痴
He's a horny idiot.
你俩对此都无能为力
Neither one of you can do anything about it.
应该是禅宗没错
Pretty sure that's Zen.
我还以为是要在卡迪的办公室碰面
Thought we were meeting in Cuddy's office.
我把手术室里的无线频率追踪器
And I put one of the radio frequency tagged sponges from the O.R.
放到你的移动电视里了
in your portable television.
无论对你来说有多难以接受
However much it hurt,
我确实有和你分手的权利
I did have a right to break up with you.
你只是希望为每件事找个私人原因
You just want everything to have a hidden personal agenda.
你得接受这一事实
You need to get over it
而非想尽一切办法破坏我们的工作
instead of torpedoing our jobs out of spite.
我可没办法像你那么惹人烦
Couldn't just be that you're a pain professionally.
都给我住嘴
Stop!
你们俩个都有错
You're both at fault here.
你知道豪斯的为人处事
You for trying to manipulate House
却还是想试图操控他
when you used to know better,
而你错在  继续做你的混蛋
and you for... Being you,
尤其在当下  无异于是雪上加霜
which an especially bad idea under the circumstances.
我有很多好理由
I had good reasons.
你的逻辑没人能接受
You had lame rationalizations.
即使我没那么做
If I hadn't played him,
他还是会知道见面的事情  一样会捣乱
he'd have found out about the meeting and crashed it anyway.
但那就不用绕这么大个圈子
Would have been a lot more efficient.
够了  你们听好了
Enough! Okay, here's what's gonna happen.
明天我开车带你们俩个去艾琳家
Tomorrow I drive both of you to Arlene's.
你给她写一张三万块的支票
You're gonna write her a personal check for $30,000,
告诉她你愿意让她住在
and tell her she can stay in her own home
自己的房子里
with your blessing.
你一定要这么做
You're gonna do this
因为你把工作  医院
because you actually give a crap about your job
还有你母亲都看得很重
and this hospital and your mother,
你甚至也在乎豪斯
and possibly even House.
而你  要说"对不起"
And you're gonna say, "I'm sorry,"
除此之外不要再多说一个字
and not utter one syllable more.
因为我是个白痴吗
Because I'm an idiot?
不  因为你不这样做  我会让药房
No, because if you don't, I'm gonna tell the pharmacy
停止发放所有以我的名义开的维柯丁
to stop issuing Vicodin prescriptions in my name.
我可不是为了猜对你耍诡计做弥补
I'm not paying for guess.
有什么变化吗
Anything look different?
还没有
Not yet.
詹妮弗人呢
Where's Jennifer?
她跑去偷我瑞士银行账户里的钱了
She's embezzling money from my Swiss bank account.
你就是这么想的  对不对
That's what you think, isn't it?
她在骗我
I'm being taken for a ride?
我在想如果你还在靠修冰箱过活
I think she wouldn't be here
她就不会来了
if you were still fixing refrigerators.
所谓本性难移
One random set of numbers
一组随机中奖号码改变不了什么
doesn't change human nature.
但正是彩票给了我希望
Those sets of numbers are what kept me going.
紧握着那些彩票
Clutching those tickets,
畅想我以后的生活
thinking about the life I could have,
和詹妮弗重逢
finding Jennifer again.
所以你认为一个做了很久的梦实现之后
So you figure if one long-shot dream came true
另一个也会实现
the other one will as well?
你觉得你是在保护我
You think you're protecting me.
我却觉得你很可悲
I think you're sad.
见不得别人幸福
Can't stand to see somebody happy.
妈  这是支票
Mom, here's a check.
算是对你所遭受一切的补偿
It's a settlement for all you've been through.
你当然可以住在自己家里
Of course you can stay in your home.
我不应该提出其它异议
It was wrong of me to suggest otherwise.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们不该自作主张救了你
That we saved your life.
我们处理的方式确实不太好
In the way that we did.
良减
B-plus.
我希望现在我们可以冰释前嫌了
I hope this resolves everything.
可以说不管是你女儿还是豪斯医生
I can tell you that both your daughter and Dr. House--
这是三万块
This is 30 grand.
这是你要求的数目
Which is what you asked for.
这只够补偿我经受的痛苦与折磨
This covers pain and suffering.
遗嘱认证律师的费用怎么办
What about the probate lawyer?
你们两位是不是...
Do you two...
这样一来  我不得不去改遗嘱
I have to change my will,
把所有财产留给朱丽叶
leave everything to Julia
好让这个女儿不再耍阴招
so this one doesn't try more funny business
以图占据我的家
to get control of my home.
我想我们可以再多付2500块
I'm sure we can toss in another 2,500.
那我想今晚我就得杀了你了
Well, I guess I'll have to kill you tonight then.
妈  我没兴趣去惦记...
Mom, I'm not interested in--
你都已经认为你能控制我的身体了
You already think you own my body.
难道不会惦记我的房子吗
Why not my home too?
大家冷静一点...
Everybody stay calm, and--
你一定要赶走所有想要帮助你的人吗
You have to lash out at everyone who tries to help you?
你就自己住这小地方吧  我才不在乎
Live in your own kitchen sink for all I care.
真犀利
Harsh.
我觉得你从没这样过
I didn't think you had a case before,
但可不能用这种态度对待病人
but that is no way to talk to a patient.
你说的没错
You are right.
奇斯盯上这姑娘有好几个月了
Chase has had his eyes on this one for months.
你是说他对她有意思
Meaning he has eyes?
我给了这姑娘一百
I paid her 100 bucks.
今晚  或者下周
When he hits on her--
只要他对她采取攻势
might be tonight, might be next week--
她就扇奇斯一巴掌走人
she's gonna slap him and storm off.
你的计划是想证明你们俩个
So your plan is to prove you're both full of crap
都是废物吗
all in one move?
第一  他会称赞她的头发
First he'll compliment her hair.
活跃下气氛
That's how he breaks the ice.
接下来  他要说点笑话小故事什么的
Next comes some kind of joke or story.
就要准备开始他的柔情攻势了
He's sharpening his harpoon.
我的行为也是这么有规律吗
Are my moves this predictable?
她会抓住他的手臂
She's grabbing his arm.
他就要出手了
He's going in for the kill.
别太在意了
Don't let it get to you.
我们在火上浇了好些油了
Poured a lot of gas on the fire.
超声波能让我们看清肿瘤的发展
Ultrasound will give us a good look at the damage.
再来一点检测剂
Little more gel.
我还没立过遗嘱呢
I never made a will.
如果我发生了什么  我想为你做点准备...
I want to provide for you, if I don't--
别瞎说了  行吗
Stop it, will you?
请憋气
Like you to hold your breath for a sec.
你的钱  应该用到慈善事业和其它需要上
Your money, there's charities, causes.
比如留给你的家人
Your family.
你应该问问自己  这么多年以来
You got to ask yourself what's mattered to you most
什么对你最重要
year in and year out.
不应该是这样
That can't be right.
是坏消息吗
Is it bad news?
不
No.
我们已经在给你输生长因子
We've been pumping you with growth factor,
但你的癌细胞并没有进一步发展
but you don't have any new cancers.
肿瘤全都收缩了
The tumors you had all shrank.
三个肿瘤的消失说明
Three tumors disappearing means we were probably wrong
之前我们缺失抑癌基因的诊断是错的
about him missing a tumor-suppressor gene.
有了上次的结果  你还不死心啊
How many mulligans are you gonna ask for?
这个测试才是我血压上升的原因
This test is what raised my blood pressure.
不过我现在习惯了
I'm used to it now.
开始吧
Go.
如果是自身免疫系统
If it's autoimmune
和他自身产生了
and he created antibodies
终止肿瘤发展的抗体
that ended up fighting his own tumors...
生长因子就能够
Growth factor would have made
改善他的自身免疫情况
the underlying autoimmune condition better.
或许他的病因就不是癌症
Maybe it was never cancer in the first place.
当然是癌  我们活检证实了
Of course it was cancer. We biopsied.
可能是假阳性
It could have been a false positive.
淀粉样变性呢
Amyloidosis?
他心电图的电压是正常范围内的低值
His EKG voltage has been on the low end of normal.
如果肿瘤其实是蛋白质沉积物呢
What if the tumors were actually protein deposits?
给他做消化道活检  开始化疗
G.I. biopsy to confirm, chemo to treat.
她的诊断依据是
She's making that diagnosis
病人的心电图电压为正常范围内的低值
based off of low-normal EKG.
正常范围内的低值还是正常
Low-normal is still normal.
这仪器肯定是出问题了
That thing cannot be right.
正常范围内的低值也是低值
Low-normal is still low,
而且这个仪器出问题的话
and that thing does not have money
它又得不到好处
riding on you being wrong,
我们其他人可就不是了
like the rest of us do.
奇斯搞的鬼
Chase fixed this.
我想你是把奇斯和福曼搞混了吧
Oh, I think you're confusing Chase and Foreman.
我以前就经常弄错
I used to do that all the time.
我知道这东西有猫腻
I know it's rigged.
因为你是冷静先生吗
Because you're Mr. Cool?
任何事情都不能干扰你...
Nothing could possibly faze--
因为我服了β受体阻滞剂
Because I took a beta blocker!
两次你都作弊了  对吧
Both times, right?
他的血小板还是很低
His platelet count's still low.
化疗对他来说是致命的
Chemo's still a death sentence.
对心电图正常的患者
Treating for amyloid with normal EKG
进行淀粉样变治疗无异于
is like doing heart surgery on a guy
给超重了10磅的人做心脏手术
because he's ten pounds overweight.
这太疯狂了
It's insane.
好吧  我们按你的方法干
Well, we'll do it your way--
看看你的咆哮能不能治好他
go shout at the patient till he gets better.
给他做消化道活检  开始化疗
G.I. biopsy to confirm, chemo to treat.
我有个小秘密告诉你
Here's the dirty little secret.
我认为人本性难移
I just think we are who we are.
而买彩票是件特别蠢的事
And I think lotteries are stupid.
珍妮特·海莫里德[痔疮]
Janet...Hemorrhoid?
这不是我的名字  而是我来这里的原因
That's not my name. It's why I'm here.
我现在明白了  跨格了
Oh, I see. It goes across.
我们得赶紧治
We better make this fast,
因为我要因渎职
'cause I'm about to lose
丢掉我的行医执照了
my medical license for malpractice.
这没什么稀奇的
It's nothing unusual.
我们院长的执照也要没了
The head of the hospital's about to lose hers too.
我听说卡迪把你的出门诊时间翻了好几倍
I heard Cuddy quadrupled your clinic hours.
是呀  但你知道吗
Yeah, but you know what?
看这些病人小菜一碟
I'm flying through patients.
艾琳想和你们再见一面
Arlene wants another meeting.
我知道  我有让你去转告她女儿
I know. Told my seconds to tell her seconds
她没有第二次机会了
that she gets no second chance.
确切地说  是第三次机会了
Well, technically, it's a third chance,
但我事不过三
but I don't have thirds.
卡迪基本上也是这么跟她说的
Cuddy told her the same thing, more or less.
终于有件事让我们的意见统一了
So you got us on the same page after all.
我之前一直在想你的谬论
I've been thinking about your irrationality,
现在我倒是得出一个合理的解释
and I've come up with a rational explanation for it.
这可真是难为你了
That's quite a challenge.
你还忘不了卡迪
You don't want to let go of Cuddy,
所以你持不合作态度
so you're clinging to the negative interaction,
因为你潜意识中觉得
because some small part of you
相互折磨比形同陌路好
thinks the bad stuff beats nothing at all.
你马上就要搞定这事了啊
You're almost making this work.
只差需要你改变事实了
All you got to do now is change reality.
说不准是我自己想要告自己呢
Perhaps if I was the one suing me.
事情不是你挑起的
You didn't start it,
但是你在有机会结束时  却没有那么做
but you had the chance to end it, and you didn't.
你爱她  豪斯
You love her, House,
不想结束是很正常的
and it's human to hang on,
但你现在这么做  不仅会毁掉你的工作
but you're blowing up not just your job
还会毁掉以后你们复合的任何可能
but any chance of any kind of relationship with her again.
这是什么
What's that?
一张支票
It's a check.
一千万美元
For $10 million.
我不知说什么好
I don't know what to say, I mean...
你已经够慷慨的了
You already been so generous.
你是说雇佣你吗
By hiring you?
支付六位数的工资给我的至亲那挡子事吗
Yeah. For a whopping six figures? My own blood?
我唯一的朋友
Best friend I ever had?
年复一年陪伴我
Year in, year out.
你眼镜里面还戴了隐形的吗
You're wearing contacts under your glasses?
我一定是  忘记摘掉了
I must have forgotten to take them off when I...
是有色的
They're tinted.
你变了瞳孔的颜色
Do you change your eye color?
偶尔换换样子
Sometimes I like to mix it up.
我不明白  你这是...
I don't understand. What are you...
等等  你不是棕色眼睛
Wait, you... you don't have brown eyes?
"熊宝宝"的昵称是从哪里来的
Where'd the name baby bear come from?
时隔太久  我记不清...
It's so long ago, I don't...
因为你左胸有块胎记
It's a birthmark on your left breast
是熊的形状
in the shape of a bear.
这都可以忘吗
You forgot that?
这是我唯一没告诉过你的事
It's the one thing I never told you.
所以她不知道
That's why she doesn't know.
不是那样的  我发誓
It's not like that. I swear.
出去
Get out.
你们两个都出去
Get out, both of you.
别这样
Come on, man.
出去
Get out.
对不起
I'm sorry.
滚出去
Get out!
都给我滚
Both of you!
你是对的
You were right.
我只是一个中彩后被骗的傻子
I'm just another lottery fool.
我的生活糟糕透顶  一直都是
My life sucks. It'll always suck.
他要不行了
He's crashing.
所有器官都在衰竭
Everything's shutting down.
病人发生心脏停搏
Patient had a cardiac arrest,
在化疗之前就出现了
and his lungs and liver failed
肺和肝功能衰竭
before we even started the chemo.
看似是脑部疾病的症状实际上不是
Brain symptoms that aren't brain symptoms,
肿瘤还能来去自如哈
tumors that come and go?
不是淀粉样变性
It's not amyloidosis.
你漏掉了脱发症
You're forgetting alopecia.
哎呀不好意思  我以为你是在
Oh, I'm sorry. I thought you were just
按字母顺序列出所有没可能的病名呢
listing the things it's not, alphabetically.
他失而复得的爱人是个冒牌货
His long lost love is a fraud.
十三发现的
Thirteen figured that out.
她真行
Good for her.
数十年的枯燥工作
Decades of menial work,
三处癌症都没能让他痛苦地死去
three cancers couldn't make him die miserable.
那女人却做到了
She just did.
真相令他痛苦
The truth made him miserable.
你说出了我的心里话
It's like there's two of me.
关闭门诊
Keep the clinic shut down.
无论火源在何处
But wherever it is,
都已经被控制在行政楼层
it's isolated to the administrative floor.
我不能疏散整个...
I'm not gonna evacuate the whole...
想让你们两个同时出现在同一地点
Only way to get the two of you
这是唯一的办法
in the same place at the same time.
关闭的部门全部开放
Reopen everything.
收治所有患者  马上
Readmit everyone. Now.
我想让你们两个知道  我今天提起诉讼
I want you both to know I'm filing the suit today,
文件将送到你律师的办公室
delivering the paperwork to your counsel's office.
你就一定要做这么绝
You have to be destructive.
不惜毁掉一切
You have to tear things apart.
千万不要告诉我
God forbid you should say
你那扭曲的心理到底想的是什么
what's really on that twisted mind of yours?
那你又好到哪里去了
And you're the great peacemaker?
单身母亲  永远留不住男人一时半刻
Single mom, can't keep a man long enough to cook a meal.
不是我们错施良药  你早没命了
You'd be dead if it weren't for our mistreatment.
可你居然还能找到抱怨的理由
And somehow you'd still find something to whine about.
我们还是让法庭判断是谁在抱怨吧
We'll let the court decide who's whining,
既然你如此坚信...
since you're so sure...
我们不会复合的
We're not getting back together.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
这是唯一的解释
It's the only explanation.
她为何一直威胁
Why she keeps making threats
却迟迟不递交
without ever filing her stupid,
那虽然愚蠢却胜算很大的诉状
yet completely valid lawsuit.
为何更改遗嘱
Why she ripped up her will,
为何把半间医院的人都弄到街上来
why she kicked half the hospital out on the street.
她想让我们联合起来对付她
She wants us united against her.
这不过是她为之前一系列所谓的侮辱
This is her drawing blood over the latest of
而进行的报复
a long line of imaginary slights.
她这辈子从没考虑过其他人的幸福
She doesn't care if anyone else is happy for a single...
看看你们这对傻瓜
Look at you idiots.
除了彼此谁还能受得了你们呢
Who else is gonna put up with either of you?
我请你搬来住
I asked you to move in.
就是表示我们不可能复合了
That meant we weren't gonna reconcile.
对不起  妈
I'm sorry, mom.
有些事不是一个共同的敌人就能改变的
Some things take more than a common enemy.
那你就是个标准太高的傻瓜
Then you're an idiot with impossible standards.
共同的敌人
Common enemy.
脑部分明没问题
One way to trigger brain symptoms
却出现脑症状  一个原因就是
when there's nothing wrong with your brain
有什么使得脑组织成为了其它部分共同的敌人
have something else turn your brain into a common enemy.
你长了畸胎瘤
You have a teratoma,
通常不会有不良影响
a usually harmless congenital growth
只是一种由各种组织填充的先天性增生物
which can be filled with almost any kind of tissue.
不寻常的是  你的瘤并非无害
And, unusually, not at all harmless.
如果我想得没错  你的瘤内填充的是原始细胞
If I'm right, yours is filled with primitive cells,
其中一些分化为神经元细胞
some of which developed into brain cells.
这些外源细胞漏入你的血液循环中
These foreign cells leaked into your bloodstream.
身体感到外源入侵
Now, the body is a little xenophobic.
就产生抗体
It creates antibodies.
麻烦在于  你肚子里的神经元细胞
The problem is, there's not much difference
与脑内的神经元细胞没有多大差别
between brain cells in your abdomen and brain cells in your brain.
更为糟糕的是
To make matters worse,
原始细胞几乎可以分化为任何细胞
primitive cells can become almost anything.
它们如杂草般疯长
Grow like weeds.
可以演变为肿瘤
Which means they can turn into tumors,
破坏全身的器官和各大系统
destroy whole organ systems.
癌症怎么解释
But the cancer?
确实是癌症
Was cancer.
只是生长太快  在自身重压下破裂了
Just growing so fast it collapsed under its own weight.
我能活下去吗
Am I gonna live?
切除畸胎瘤和残余的癌瘤
Cut out the teratoma, what's left of your cancer,
你会没事的
you should be fine.
把今天当作是你你第二幸运日好了
Think of it as your second luckiest day.
我感觉不到幸运
It's hard to feel lucky.
我爱的女人是个假象
The woman I love was a fraud.
不对  来骗你的人是假的
No, actually a fraud was a fraud.
你对她的爱依然是真的
You fell for her just the same.
你可以选择继续痛苦
You may stay miserable,
但失去已久的爱情却不是你痛苦的原因
but your long lost love is not gonna be the reason why.
是真的詹妮弗
It's the real Jennifer.
至少是唯一一个有胎记的珍妮弗
Or at least the only one to show up who actually has the birthmark.
他要给她租间公寓
He's renting her an apartment.
结局堪忧
It'll end horribly.
对他来说不会
Not for him.
她或许会骗光他的钱
She may take all his money,
他或许天真如白痴
and he may be a naive idiot, but...
但是他会一直满怀希望
He'll always be hopeful,
所以他会一直幸福下去
so he'll always be happy.
你早年丧母
You lost your mother.
亲手给哥哥安乐死
You euthanized your brother.
未来的生活注定是一出悲剧
You got the life expectancy of a pretty good Sitcom.
即便没有这些经历
If you can convince yourself
如果你还是确信
that you'd be miserable no matter what
自己命中注定会悲惨痛苦
even without all that stuff,
或许你就不必对全世界心怀怨恨
then maybe you don't have to hate the universe
不满自己命运多舛
for dumping a giant turd on you.
宿命论是你维持生存的方式
Fatalism is your survival mechanism.
那你呢
And you?
被所有你爱的人抛弃
Dumped by everyone you've ever loved.
药瘾戒了又犯
Rehab was a bust.
腿像是被人咬掉了一大块
Your leg feels like somebody took a giant bite out of it.
人是不会变的
We are who we are.
不要寄希望于突来的幸福
Lotteries are stupid.